ILGWU David Dubinsky Correspondence 5780/002
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Local 364, Port Huron, Mich, 1937 (Box 113, Folder 9)
- Local 376, Knoxville, Tenn, 1940-1941 (Box 113, Folder 10a-10b)
  Incl. correspondence. re Standard Knitting Mill Co.
- Local 384, Los Angeles, Calif, 1941-1945 (Box 114, Folder 1a-1h)
  Corres. w. Louis Levy, George Wishnak, Rose Pesotta, Elias Lieberman & officers of Local 384 re Mode O'Day Corp. impending strike & agreement; internal local conflict.
- Local 482, Brookhaven, Miss., 1948 (Box 114, Folder 2)
- Los Angeles Sanatorium, 1934-1941 (Box 115, Folder 1a-1b)
  Incl. list of Union members admitted & discharged by Sanatorium.
- Los Angeles Sanatorium, 1937-1939 (Box 115, Folder 2a-2b)
  Incl. correspondence. re Hillquit Memorial Hospital building.
- Lovestone, Jay, 1938-1939 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  Letters & reports.
- M, 1949-1951 (Box 115, Folder 4)
  Corres.
- M, 1941-1948 (Box 115, Folder 5a-5b)
  I.c.w. Max Meyer (Chairman), Millinery Code Authority, (Educational Chairman), Needlecraft Commission, 1934-46.
- M, 1938-1940 (Box 115, Folder 6a-6b)
  Apr. 1938-40.
- M, 1935-1938 (Box 116, Folder 1)
  Oct. 1935-Mar. 1938. Incl. correspondence. on Tom Mooney Case.
- M, 1935 (Box 116, Folder 2a-2b)
  April 1935-Aug. 1935. Incl. correspondence. on Union film, "Marching On."
- M, 1933-1935 (Box 116, Folder 3)
  1933-Feb. 1935. Incl. correspondence. on May Day Celebration, 1933.
- Management-Engineering Dept., 1940-1949 (Box 116, Folder 4)
  I.c.w. William Gomberg; reports.
- Markewich and Null, 1937-1940 (Box 116, Folder 5)
- Mayor's Business Advisory Comm. (Fiorello H. LaGuardia, Mayor), 1943-1944 (Box 117, Folder 1)
  Corres. re Government contracts, business & labor matters; comm. memoranda & reports.
- Mayor's Business Advisory Committee, 1942 (Box 117, Folder 2a-2b)
- Mayor's Business Advisory Committee, 1940-1941 (Box 117, Folder 3a-3b)
- McGrady, Edward F., Asst. Secretary of Labor, 1931-1935 (Box 117, Folder 4)
- Medalie, George Z., 1934 (Box 117, Folder 5)
- Merchant's Ladies Garment Association, Inc., 1937-1940 (Box 117, Folder 6a-6b)
  I.c.w. Joseph Dubow (Exec. Dir.) on Negotiations of Agreements.
- Modigliani; Giuseppe E, 1935 (Box 118, Folder 1a-1d)
  Dec. 1934-Mar. 1935. Corres. bet. Serafino Romualdi & Union re Modigliani's lecture tour on Fascism & Labor Movement.
- Mooney, Tom, 1936-1939 (Box 118, Folder 2a-2b)
  I.c.w. Tom Mooney; Defense Comm. for Tom Mooney; Union & Comm. releases.
- N, 1947-1951 (Box 118, Folder 3)
- N, 1940-1946 (Box 119, Folder 1a-1b)
- N, 1934-1939 (Box 119, Folder 2)
- National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board, 1939-1941 (Box 119, Folder 3a-3c)
- Nat'l. Coat and Suit Ind. Rec. Bd., 1938 (Box 119, Folder 4a-4c)
- Nat'l. Coat and Suit Ind. Rec. Bd., 1937 (Box 120, Folder 1a-1d)
- Nat'l. Coat and Suit Ind. Rec. Bd., 1936 (Box 120, Folder 2a-2b)
- Nat'l. Coat and Suit Ind. Rec. Bd., 1935 (Box 120, Folder 3a-3b)
- Nat'l. Coat and Suit Ind. Rec. Board, 1942-1945 (Box 121, Folder 1a-1b)
  Administrative Comm. correspondence.
- National Committee for Labor Israel, Histadrut, 1948-1951 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  (Prior to 1949, Nat'l. Labor Comm. for Palestine) I.c.w. Joseph Schlossberg (Chairman), on committee activities & finances.
- Nat'l. Comm. for Labor Israel, 1938-1947 (Box 121, Folder 3a-3b)
- Nat'l. Comm. for Labor Israel, 1930-1937 (Box 121, Folder 4a-4b)
- NLRB Corres, 1937-1946 (Box 122, Folder 1a-1b)
  Incl. Special Committee of the House of Representatives to investigate the NLRB; D.D. testimony before Comm., Howard W. Smith, Chairman, 1939-40.
- NLRB Cases, arranged by city, A., 1939 (Box 122, Folder 2a-2b)
  I.c.w. Elias Lieberman; printed material; petitions; charges; decrees & decisions on Alpena Garment Co. Case, 1939.
- NLRB Cases, B-C. (Box 122, Folder 3a-3b)
- NLRB Cases, D-H. (Box 122, Folder 4a-4b)
- NLRB Cases, I-P. (Box 123, Folder 1a-1c)
- NLRB Cases, Q-Z. (Box 123, Folder 2a-2b)
- NLRB Newspaper Clippings File. Incl. clippings on Alpena and Donnelly Garment Co. cases. (Box 123, Folder 3)
- NRA Code for the Blouse and Skirt Industry, 1933-1935 (Box 124, Folder 1)
- NRA, Circulars (Union). (Box 124, Folder 2)
- NRA, Code for Coat and Suit Industry, 1934-1935 (Box 124, Folder 3a-3b)
  Sept. 1934-35. I.c.w. Nathan Wolf, George N. Alger (Director) re meetings, hearings, resolutions; minutes of Aug. 1934 hearing.
- NRA, Coat and Suit Industry, 1934 (Box 124, Folder 4a-4b)
  Jan-Aug. 1934.
- NRA, Coat and Suit Industry, 1933 (Box 124, Folder 5a-5b)
  Aug-Dec. 1933.
- NRA, Coat and Suit Industry, Miscellaneous Reference File, 1933-1934 (Box 125, Folder 1a-1e)
  Incl. congratulatory messages on signing code; employer proposal & Hillquit brief for Union; statistical reports on industries, proposed codes & amendments; D.D. statement at code hearings July 1933. D.D. radio talk, "Workers' or Employers' Code for Garment Industry," July 1933; stenographic notes.
- NRA Coordinator for Industrial Cooperation, 1936-1937 (Box 126, Folder 1a-1b)
  Incl. Coordinator bulletins & releases.
- NRA Coordinator for Industrial Cooperation, 1935 (Box 126, Folder 2)
  Incl. correspondence. on proposed labor legislation for garment industry.
- NRA Code for Corset and Brassiere Industry. Incl. code. (Box 126, Folder 3)
- NRA Code for Cotton Garment Industry, 1933-1935 (Box 126, Folder 4a-4b)
  Incl. hearings, transcript of public hearing, Aug. 1933; correspondence. on lowering work hours to 36.
- NRA Code for Covered Button Industry, 1933 (Box 126, Folder 5)
  Incl. codes.
- NRA Code for Dress Industry, 1933-1935 (Box 127, Folder 1a-1c)
  I.c.w. Byres H. Gitchell (Director), Morris Kolchin (Secretary), Dress Code Authority; reports; proposed amendments; codes for Dress Industry, 1933.
- NRA, Dress Industry. (Box 127, Folder 2)
- NRA, Dress Industry, 1933 (Box 127, Folder 3a-3d)
  Incl. drafts of code submitted by mfrs. Assoc; D.D. proposed modifications; notes & correspondence.
- NRA Code for Embroidery, Pleating and Stitching Industry, 1933 (Box 128, Folder 1)
- NRA Code for Handkerchief Industry, 1933 (Box 128, Folder 2)
- NRA Code for Infants' and Children's Wear Industry, 1933-1935 (Box 128, Folder 3)
- NRA Labor Bureau, Coat and Suit Industry, 1933 (Box 128, Folder 4)
  Report.
- NRA Labor Bureau, Coat A Suit Industry, 1934 (Box 128, Folder 5)
- NRA Code for Ladies Neckwear Industry, 1933-1934 (Box 128, Folder 6)
- NRA Madison Square Garden Meeting, 1953 (Box 128, Folder 7)
  May 1935. Demonstration for "A Greater & Stronger NRA" and for pro-labor legislation.
- NRA, New York City, 1933-1934 (Box 128, Folder 8)
  I.c.w. Grover A. Whalen (Chairman), NYC-NRA Comm.; minutes of meetings of the Compliance Board, Nov. 3-7, 1933.
- NRA, 1934-1937 (Box 128, Folder 9)
- NRA Proceedings, 1933 (Box 129, Folder 1a-1d)
  June-Oct. 1933. Arranged chronologically No. 1-87.
- NRA, Washington, 1935-1936 (Box 129, Folder 2a-2c)
  Corres. w. NRA Depts.; D.D. statement at public hearing on employment policy, Feb. 1935.
- NRA, Washington, 1933-1934 (Box 130, Folder 1a-1d)
- National Youth Administration, 1940-1941 (Box 130, Folder 2)
- Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union, 1933-1935 (Box 130, Folder 3)
  Letters from Ben Gold, Louis Hyman urging unity in garment industry by proposing joint campaigns; D.D. statements.
- Negro Labor Committee, 1935-1938 (Box 130, Folder 4)
  I.c.w. Frank R. Crosswaith; minutes, broadsides & releases.
- New Leader, 1933-1939 (Box 130, Folder 5)
- New York World's Fair, 1940 (Box 131, Folder 1)
- New York World's Fair, 1939 (Box 131, Folder 2a-2b)
  Incl. correspondence. on Union apparel exhibit & purchasing of bonds.
- Northeast Dept. See Joint Boards Cotton and Dress Misc. Trades Dept. & Elias Reisberg. (Box 131, Folder 3)
- O, 1933-1945 (Box 131, Folder 4)
- O'Dwyer, William, 1946-1951 (Box 131, Folder 5)
  Incl. correspondence. re Mayor's Committee Golden Anniversary.
- ORT, 1939-1944 (Box 131, Folder 6a-6b)
  (Organization for Rehabilitation through Training in Industry & Agriculture)
- P, 1940-1950 (Box 131, Folder 7a-7b)
- P, 1933-1939 (Box 132, Folder 1a-1b)
- Perlmutter, Samuel, 1934-1941 (Box 132, Folder 2)
- Perlstein, Meyer, 1940-1946 (Box 132, Folder 3)
- Perlstein, Meyer, 1938-1939 (Box 132, Folder 4a-4b)
- Perlstein, Meyer, 1937 (Box 132, Folder 5a-5c)
- Perlstein, Meyer, 1936 (Box 133, Folder 1a-1c)
- Perlstein, Meyer, 1935 (Box 133, Folder 2a-2c)
- Perlstein, Meyer, 1934 (Box 134, Folder 1a-1b)
- Pesotta, Rose, 1938-1942 (Box 134, Folder 2)
- Pesotta, Rose, 1934-1937 (Box 134, Folder 3)
- Plettl, Martin, 1934-1938 (Box 134, Folder 4a-4b)
  (Former President, Clothing Workers Union of Germany).
- Poletti, Charles, 1946-1947 (Box 134, Folder 5)
- Politics, Campaign, 1951 (Box 135, Folder 1a-1b)
  Rudolph Halley's campaign for President of City Council, NYC.
- Politics, Campaign, 1950 (Box 135, Folder 2a-2e)
- Campaigns of Herbert Lehman, Walter A. Lynch, Ferdinand Pecora; Union analysis of campaigns; minutes of ILGWU Campaign Committee, 1952 (Box 136, Folder 1a)
  meeting of NYC Union officers, Oct. 2, 1952
- Campaigns of Herbert Lehman, Walter A. Lynch, Ferdinand Pecora; Union analysis of campaigns; minutes of ILGWU Campaign Committee (Box 136, Folder 1b-1c)
  printed material.
- Franklin D. Roosevelt, Jr., for Congress; William O'Dwyer, Newbold Morris for Mayor; correspondence. and statements dealing with division of opinion within Liberal Party & Union on mayoralty candidates; Harold Ickes letter re Herbert H. Lehman campaig, 1949 (Box 136, Folder 2a-2c)
  correspondence. on NYC & NYS elections
- Franklin D. Roosevelt, Jr., for Congress; William O'Dwyer, Newbold Morris for Mayor; correspondence. and statements dealing with division of opinion within Liberal Party & Union on mayoralty candidates; Harold Ickes letter re Herbert H. Lehman campaig, 1949 (Box 136, Folder 2d-2e)
  Congressional & State elections. Arranged alphabetically by state
- Politics, Campaign, 1948 (Box 137, Folder 1a-1c)
  Gen. correspondence., contributions to Labor League for Political Education.
- Politics, Campaign, 1948 (Box 137, Folder 1d-1f)
  NYC & NYS campaigns.
- Politics, Campaign, 1948 (Box 137, Folder 1g)
  Locals, ILGWU Campaign Committee minutes.
- Politics, Campaign, 1948 (Box 137, Folder 1h)
  Congratulatory messages to D.D. on victories in municipal & national elections,
- Politics, Campaign, 1948 (Box 137, Folder 1i)
  Printed material; Truman itinerary on NYC visit; Union reports.
- Politics, Campaign, 1947 (Box 138, Folder 1)
  Incl. correspondence. on Union's voter registration drive and efforts to repeal Taft-Hartley Law.
- Politics, Campaign, 1946 (Box 138, Folder 2a-2b)
  Incl. correspondence. on campaigns of James M. Mead & Herbert Lehman.
- Politics, Campaign, 1945 (Box 138, Folder 3a-3c)
  Incl. correspondence. on campaigns of Jonah J. Goldstein, Joseph D. McGoldrick & Nicholas M. Pette.
- Politics, Campaign, 1944 (Box 139, Folder 1a-1h)
  Incl. correspondence. on Presidential campaign, Franklin D. Roosevelt & Harry S Truman letters. 1a-1c. Gen. correspondence. 1d. Corres. on state campaigns. 1f-1g. Union-sponsored broadcasts. 1h. Printed material.
- Politics, Campaign, 1943 (Box 140, Folder 1a-1d)
  I.c.w. Trade Union Committee on Salvatore Ninfo campaign and Committee report; correspondence. on campaign of Matthew M. Levy; American Labor Party enrollment drive; newspaper clippings.
- Politics, Campaign, 1942 (Box 140, Folder 2a-2d)
  Corres. w. A.L.P. on NYC campaigns; D.D. speech, 1944; newspaper clippings.
- Politics, Campaign, 1940 (Box 141, Folder 1a-1e)
  Incl. correspondence. on Presidential campaign; campaigns of James M. Mead & Caroline O'Day; D.O. & Luigi Antonini speeches at A.L.P. rally, Madison Sq. Garden, Oct.; request for Roosevelt supplement of Justice; newspaper clippings.
- Politics, Campaign, 1939 (Box 141, Folder 2)
  Incl. exchange of letters from D.D., Alex Rose, Luigi Antonini w. Adolph A. Berle on candidate for Brooklyn D.A.
- Politics, Campaign, 1938 (Box 141, Folder 3a-3c)
  Corres. on NYC campaign; controversy with ALP on candidacy for Senator, Herbert H. Lehman vs Sidney Hillman; Norman Thomas letter praising Union & criticizing ALP policies.
- Politics, Campaign, 1936 (Box 142, Folder 1a-1f)
  Corres. on Presidential campaign; Union press releases; D.D. speech at ALP rally, Nov.; correspondence. dealing with attacks on D.D. by Republican Party & John Hamilton (Republican National Chairman) calling D.D. a communist; incl. editorials on issue; newspaper clippings & Union pamphlet. The Dubinsky Issue.
- Politics, Americans for Democratic Action, 1949-1951 (Box 142, Folder 2a-2b)
  Corres. w. Francis Biddle, Hubert H. Humphrey, James Loeb, Jr., & Joseph Rauh, Jr; Union contributions to ADA; correspondence. on invitation to Adam Clayton Powell to participate in work of Legislative Committee for ADA Convention, 1950.
- Politics, ADA, 1948 (Box 143, Folder 1a-1b)
  I.c.w. Leon Henderson & Hubert H. Humphrey.
- Politics, ADA, 1947 (Box 143, Folder 2a-2c)
  I.c.w. Joseph P. Lash & John F.P. Tucker; minutes of Organizing Committee, Jan.
- Politics, American Labor Party, 1942-1944 (Box 143, Folder 3a-3c)
  Corres. on campaigns; text of new Liberal-Labor Party program by Hudson Valley District, ALP, 1944.
- Politics, ALP, 1941 (Box 144, Folder 1a-1c)
  Corres. on NYC elections; re-election of Fiorello H. LaGuardia; text of Wendell Willkie speech before ALP rally, Oct.
- Politics, ALP, 1937-1940 (Box 144, Folder 2a-2b)
  Incl. correspondence. on Communist influence in 1940 elections; Alex Rose letters.
- Politics, ALP, 1937-1938 (Box 144, Folder 3a-3e)
  I.c.w. Alex Rose on 1937 mayoralty campaign, NYC. list of candidates endorsed by ALP. Union contribution to Party and printed material.
- Politics, ALP, 1936 (Box 145, Folder 1)
  Nov-Dec. 1936. Incl. congratulatory message to D.D. upon re-election of Roosevelt; finances.
- Politics, ALP, 1936 (Box 145, Folder 2a-2c)
  July-Oct. 1936. I.c.w. Union officers & members, Elinore M. Herrick (State Campaign Director); Benjamin Mandel letter to State Executive Committee of ALP opposing cooperation w. Communists, Aug.
- Politics, ALP Labor Club, 1938-1940 (Box 145, Folder 3)
  Incl. correspondence. & minutes of meetings.
- Politics, ALP, Liberal and Labor Committee, 1944 (Box 145, Folder 4a-4b)
  Incl. statements, releases, advertisements on 1944 primary contest in ALP, incl. those of Hillman & LaGuardia.
- Politics, ALP, Newspaper Clippings and Releases, 1940 (Box 145, Folder 5)
  Incl. D.D. statement on Louis Waldman for Waldman's attacks on him, Alex Rose & ALP.
- Politics, ALP, Newspaper Clippings and Releases, 1938-1939 (Box 145, Folder 6)
- Politics, ALP, Newspaper Clippings and Releases, 1936-1937 (Box 146, Folder 1a-1b)
  Incl. constitution, rules, by-laws, bulletins & minutes of exec. comm. meetings.
- Politics, Communist Party, 1944-1948 (Box 146, Folder 2a-2b)
  Incl. correspondence. on Communist activities in labor, newspaper clippings.
- Politics, Communist Party, 1940-1943 (Box 146, Folder 3a-3c)
  Incl. newspaper clippings on Dies Committee hearings, 1940
- Politics, Communist Party, 1937-1939 (Box 146, Folder 4a-4b)
  Incl. minutes of 10th Convention of CP, May 1938.
- Politics, Farmer-Labor Party (Farmer-Labor Political Federation), 1934-1939 (Box 147, Folder 1a-1b)
  Incl. correspondence. on Union activities in Minnesota; correspondence. w. Alfred M. Bingham (Exec. Secy.); contribution by Union to Party.
- Politics, Inauguration, 1949 (Box 147, Folder 2)
  (Harry S Truman)
- Politics, Individuals, 1937-1949 (Box 147, Folder 3a-3b)
  Arranged alphabetically by state. Corres. on candidates supported by Union; correspondence. w. Roosevelt on Dean Alfange for U.S. attorney for the Southern District.
- Politics, ILGWU, 1944-1947 (Box 147, Folder 4)
  Incl. Political Dept. reports.
- Politics, Labor's League for Political Education, 1948-1955 (Box 147, Folder 5a-5c)
  I.c.w. James L. McDevitt, Joseph D. Keenan & Wm. Green on campaign activities, reports.
- Politics, Labor's League for Political Education, 1948-1949 (Box 148, Folder 1a-1d)
  Corres. w. League on 1948 campaign; incl. reports, constitution, amendments, minutes of Nov. 1948 meeting.
- Politics, Labor's Non-Partisan League, 1939-1941 (Box 148, Folder 2)
  Corres. & bulletins.
- Politics, Labor's Non-Partisan League, 1932-1938 (Box 148, Folder 3a-3b)
- Politics, Labor's Non-Partisan League, 1936 (Box 149, Folder 1a-1c)
  I.c.w. George L. Berry (Pres.) on presidential & senatorial campaigns; news releases; Berry addresses.
- Politics, Liberal Party, 1949-1950 (Box 149, Folder 2a-2c)
  I.c.w. Ben Davidson (Exec. Dir.) on 1950 N.Y. State elections; Herbert Lehman, Walter A. Lynch & Ferdinand Pecora; Liberal Party memoranda & releases.
- Politics, Liberal Party, 1948 (Box 149, Folder 3a-3b)
  Incl. D.D. address at Liberal Party rally, Oct; address by Adolph A. Berle, Jr. to State Convention of ADA, April.
- Politics, Liberal Party, 1947 (Box 149, Folder 4a-4c)
- Politics, Liberal Party, 1945-1946 (Box 150, Folder 1a-1b)
  Incl. resignation letter from John C. Childs (Chairman), Dec. 1946.
- Politics, Liberal Party, 1944 (Box 150, Folder 2a-2b)
  Corres. on formation of Party & Roosevelt re-election.
- Politics, Socialist Party, 1934-1940 (Box 150, Folder 3a)
  Incl. letters from Norman Thomas.
- Politics, States and Canada, 1943-1949 (Box 150, Folder 3b)
  Corres. on campaigns in States; correspondence. w. David Lewis (Nat'l. Secy.), Cooperative Commonwealth Federation of Canada; arranged alphabetically by State, separate division for Canada.
- Politics, States and Canada, 1942 (Box 150, Folder 3c)
  Incl. letters from Joseph E. Casey (Senator, Mass.), George W. Norris (Senator, Nebr.).
- R, 1940-1950 (Box 150, Folder 4a-4c)
  Incl. correspondence. on D.D.'s crossing picket line at Waldorf-Astoria, April 1946.
- R, 1933-1939 (Box 151, Folder 1a-1b)
- Rand School of Social Science, 1934-1939 (Box 151, Folder 1c)
  I.c.w. Algernon Lee (Pres.).
- Refugees, Displaced Persons, 1946-1952 (Box 151, Folder 2a-2b)
  Corres. re Union efforts to bring refugees from Shanghai to U.S.; corres­pondents incl. Emil Schlesinger & Harry R. Rosenfield (Commissioner, Displaced Persons Commission); James Lipsig report on bringing Polish Garment Workers to U.S., Sept. 1946; testimony before U.S. Senate Sub-Committee on Immigration on behalf of the Union by James Lipsig & report by Schlesinger on DP problem.
- Refugees, Jewish Labor Committee (JLC), 1940-1942 (Box 151, Folder 3a-3b)
  Corres. re activities of Union & JLC in obtaining visas for refugees; correspondence. incl. Luigi Antonini, Jacob Pat (Exec. Sec'y, JLC), Moses A. Leavitt (Sec'y), American Jewish Joint Distribution Com­mittee, & Roy Atherton (Acting Chief), Division of European Affairs.
- Refugees, National Refugee Service, Inc., 1939-1943 (Box 151, Folder 4a-4b)
  I.c.w. William Rosenwald (Pres.); reports & summaries of Nat'l. Refugee Service meetings.
- Refugees, U.S. Committee for the Care of European Children, Inc., 1941-1947 (Box 151, Folder 5a-5b)
  Corres. w. Marshall Field (Pres.) re Union contributions in behalf of refugees.
- Reisberg, Elias, 1940-1945 (Box 152, Folder 1a-1b)
  Incl. letters of condolence on his death, Aug. 1943; also correspondence. re dedication of the S.S. Elias Reisberg, 1945.
- Corres. re collections by Union affiliates. (Box 152, Folder 1a-1c)
- Reisberg, Elias, 1938 (Box 152, Folder 2a-2b)
  I.c.w. Reisberg on Union activities in Mass., Pa., & R.I.
- Reisberg, Elias, 1937 (Box 152, Folder 3a-3c)
- Reisberg, Elias, 1934-1936 (Box 152, Folder 4a-4b)
  I.c.w. Sam Otto on Union activities in Pa.
- Relief Fund (ILGWU War Relief Fund), 1946 (Box 152, Folder 5a-5b)
- Relief Fund (ILGWU War Relief Fund), 1945 (Box 153, Folder 2a-2e)
  Collections.
- Req. A. (Box 153, Folder 3)
- Req. A., 1940 (Box 154, Folder 1a-1c)
  Incl. American Cancer Society, American League for Relief of Jews in Poland, American League for Peace and Democracy, American Red Cross, American Youth Congress; I.c.w. Eleanor Roosevelt on AYC, 1940.
- Req. B. (Box 154, Folder 2a-2b)
  Incl. Brooklyn Federation of Jewish Charities.
- Req. C. (Box 154, Folder 3a-3b)
- Req. C., 1935-1949 (Box 155, Folder 1a-1b)
  Incl. The Churchman, correspondence. w. Harold L. Ickes re Churchman Award Dinner, 1949; Commentary. Committee for the Defense of Civil Rights in Tampa, 1935-37.
- Req. D-E. (Box 155, Folder 2a-2b)
- Req. F., 1937-1938 (Box 155, Folder 3a-3b)
  Incl. Federation for the Support of Jewish Philanthropic Societies & their affiliates; Vincento Ferrero deportation case, 1937-38; Freedom House, Inc. (Wilkie Memorial Bldg.).
- Req. G. (Box 155, Folder 4)
- Req. G., 1938-1944 (Box 156, Folder 1a-1c)
  Greater N.Y. Fund, Inc., 1938 campaign. Incl. Greater N.Y. Fund cases arranged alphabetically by surname, 1938-44.
- Req. H. (Box 156, Folder 1d)
- Req. I. (Box 156, Folder 1e)
- Req. J., 1937-1942 (Box 156, Folder 2a-2b)
  Incl. Jewish Peoples Comm.
- Req. K., 1937-1939 (Box 156, Folder 3)
  Incl. Keep America Out of War Congress, 1938-39; Kentucky Miners Defense, 1937.
- Req. L. (Box 156, Folder 4)
- Req. M. (Box 157, Folder 1a-1b)
- Req. N. (Box 157, Folder 1c-11)
  Incl. Nat'l. Assoc. for the Advancement of Colored People; Nat'1. Urban League; Negro Labor Committee; correspondence. w. Frank Crosswaith (Chairman); Neue Volkszetung; New School for Social Research; New York University, College of Medicine.
- Req. O. (Box 158, Folder 1a-1b)
  Incl. Organization for Rehabilitation Through Training (ORT).
- Req. P., 1936 (Box 158, Folder 2a-2b)
  Incl. Pioneer Youth of America; correspondence. on project for a camp under the auspices of the Union.
- Req. Q-R., 1934-1940 (Box 158, Folder 3a-3b)
  Incl. Relief Society for Socialist Prisoners & Exiles in Soviet Russia.
- Req. S., 1938-1939 (Box 158, Folder 4a-4b)
  Incl. Southern Conf. for Human Welfare.
- Req. S. (Box 158, Folder 5)
  Sanatoriums.
- Req. T. (Box 159, Folder 1a)
  I.c.w. or about Terzani Defense Comm; incl. letters from Norman Thomas (Chairman), 1933-34; Carlo Tresca case, 1944-47.
- Req. U-V. (Box 159, Folder 1b-1c)
- Req. W., 1935-1947 (Box 159, Folder 1d-1e)
  Incl. Workers Alliance of America, 1935-39. Workers Defense League, 1937-47.
- Req. Y-Z. (Box 159, Folder 2)
- Requests for Union agreements. (Box 159, Folder 3a-3b)
- Req., Special Cases, 1937-1951 (Box 160, Folder 1a-1c)
  Individuals requesting financial assistance or Union positions; correspondence. w. institutions to help individuals remain in U.S. NOTE: Most of the correspondence. deals w. individuals whose surnames begin w. G or H.
- Research Dept., 1945-1951 (Box 160, Folder 2a-2b)
  Reports & related correspondence. on the garment industry; incl. statement by Lazare Teper on monopoly power before the Judiciary Comm., House of Rep., July 1949; letters from Broadus Mitchell and Elias Lieberman on status of Mennonites in Union shops & Union proposal, 1945.
- Rivera Murals. Corres. and pamphlet on murals, 1940-1951 (Box 161, Folder 1)
- Roewer, George, 1931-1939 (Box 161, Folder 2)
  Corres. legal matters.
- Romualdi, Serafino, 1937-1953 (Box 161, Folder 3a-3b)
  Incl. correspondence. & reports on trade unions in Latin America
- Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1930-1950 (Box 161, Folder 4a-4b)
  Incl. correspondence. w. organizations on FDR memorials; two invitations to White House, Feb. 1942 & Mar. 1943.
- FDR Birthday Balls, 1939-1950 (Box 161, Folder 5a-5b)
  Union participation in fund drive for Nat'l. Foundation for Infantile Paralysis; incl. 1. from FDR on Union support of drive in 1944.
- FDR Birthday Ball, 1938 (Box 161, Folder 6)
  Jan. 1938. Corres. on D.D.'s acceptance of membership on Nat'l. Labor Comm. for the President's Birthday Celebration.
- FDR, Bust, 1947 (Box 161, Folder 7a-7b)
  Presented by Union to FDR Library at Hyde Park, Jan. 20, 1947; incl. dedication statement by D.D.
- Roosevelt House, N.Y. (Box 162, Folder 1a)